Finding Aid for the John Crowe Ransom Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Sakmyster – Silvers (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Simmons – Simpson (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Smith – Swartz (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Tate – Tuony (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Unger – Voss (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Wagner – Watkins (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Watts – Wright (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Incoming Correspondence:, Yoken – Zabel (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Incoming Correspondence: Unidentified:, Bob – Tom (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Incoming Correspondence: Unidentified:, Fragments (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Incoming Correspondence: Miscellaneous:, March 13, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Incoming Correspondence: Miscellaneous:, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Series II: Writings
  - Poetry: Unpublished (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Daily”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Hallowe’en Poem”, Photocopy of Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “I Would Do Violence”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Mother and Child”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “My Dog”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “Question and Answer”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “This Lady”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poetry: Published (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Agitato Ma Non Troppo”, Typescript, photocopy of incomplete typescript and photocopy from published version (New York Review), with corrections, 3 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Antique Harvesters”, Typescript with corrections, 3 pages, one titled “Harvesters for the Lady” (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Bells for John Whiteside’s Daughter”, Typescript and photocopy from publication, 3 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Birthday of the Seer”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Blue Girls”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Captain Carpenter”, Typescript with corrections, 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Cloak Model”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Dead Boy”, Typescript and photocopy from publication, 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Dog”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Eclogue”, Typescript with corrections, 3 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Emily Hardcastle, Spinster”, Typescript and photocopy from publication, 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “First Travels of Max”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Four Threesomes; or Three Foursomes?”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Grim Wedlock”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (variant of “In Process of a Noble Alliance”) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Her Eyes”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Here Lies a Lady”, Page from publication, with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Janet Waking”, Photocopy from publication, 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Judith of Bethulia”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Man Without Sense of Direction”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Master’s in the Garden Again”, Typescript with corrections, 10 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Miller’s Daughter”, Typescript with corrections, 4 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Miriam Tazewell”, Typescript with corrections and photocopy from publication, 2 pages (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Miss Euphemia”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Moments of Minnie”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “Necrological”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Poetry: Published (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Of Margaret”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Old Mansion”, Typescript with corrections, 5 pages (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “On the Road to Wockensutter”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Parting at Dawn”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Parting, Without a Sequel”, Typescript, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Piazza Piece”, Typescript and photocopy from publication, 3 pages (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “The Rose”, Typescript with correction, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Survey of Literature”, Typescript and photocopy from publication, with corrections, 5 pages (also titled “Roll-Call of Eminent Poets and How They Subsisted”) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “These Winters and Those”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Two in August”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “The Vanity of the Bright Young Men”, Typescript with corrections, 9 pages (also titled “Tom, Tom, The Piper’s Son”) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “Vision by Sweetwater”, Typescript with corrections, 2 pages “What Ducks Require”, Typescript with corrections, 1 page “Winter Remembered”, Photocopy from publication, 1 page (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Poetry: Anthology (1 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Anthology, Typescript partial table of contents and miscellaneous poems by various American and English poets (c. 100 items), some with annotation. Appears to be a draft of a proposed anthology of poetry, though some poems may have been typed for use in a lecture or reading. List of poets and authors provided in file. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Poetry: Anthology (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Same as above. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Poetry: Anthology (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Same as above. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Prose: “The Creative Artist In America” (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Holograph speech or lecture (possibly given at Penn State), 13 pages (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Prose: “Editorial Note: The Meters” (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Holograph editorial note apparently for the Kenyon Review, 3 pages (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Prose: “Empirics in Politics” (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Issue of the Kenyon Review (Vol. XV, Autumn, 1953), with this essay revised by hand and to which are appended 4 pages of holograph notes apparently for the version that appeared in Poems and Essays (1955). (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Prose: “Fifty Years of American Verse” (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections, c. 1961, 5 pages. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Prose: “The Final Cause of Poetry” (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Multiple typescript drafts with corrections and holograph notes of a speech given to Lambda Iota Tau Fraternity, c. [1966], 41 pages. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Prose: “The Idea of a Literary Anthropologist” (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Holograph draft (lacking first page), probably of the article by this title, which was published in the Kenyon Review [1959], 15 pages. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Prose: “Introduction” (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections of the Introduction to Selected Poems of Thomas Hardy (1960), 10 pages. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Prose: “Thomas Hardy” (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Typescript with corrections of an entry that appeared in The Concise Encyclopedia of English and American Poets and Poetry, 5 pages. (See correspondence from Tony Raven and Jocelyn Selson for further information regarding this project.) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Prose: “La nd” (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Typescript with corrections, consisting of four chapters: Preface, 7 pages, 1 “Homeless People and Vacant Land,” 21 pages 2 “The Excess of Capital,” 32 pages 3 “Some Proposed Extinguishers,” 31 pages 4 “The Amphibian Farmer,” 35 pages (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Prose: “A Little Bit of Nostalgia, And A Note Of Hope” (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Typescript with correction, probably a speech about Robert Lowell, c. [1961], 4 pages. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Prose: Masters and Friends, “Introduction” (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Typescript and holograph drafts with corrections, of an Introduction to Volume 9 of a fifteen volume Bollingen series of the works Paul Valery, 87 pages. (See correspondence from Jackson Mathews for more information on this project.) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Prose: Masters and Friends, “Introduction” (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Continued from above. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Prose: “M r. L ew is ’ Tee t h” (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Typescript with corrections, 16 pages. Apparently written in response to “What Is The Use of Art, Anyway” by Coomaraswamy. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Prose: “New Poets and Old Muses” (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Typescript with corrections, 26 pages. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Prose: “No Hay” (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Typescript fragment of a short story written under the pseudonym John Creveling, 8 pages. (Verso of title page reads “No Hay by John Crowe Ra”) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Prose: “The Poet Laureate” (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Typescript of an article published in the Literary Review (1924), 8 pages. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Prose: “The Postmaster” (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Typescript fragment of a short story “for the Short Story Contest,” 20 pages. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - (Most likely written for the Sigma Upsilon contest while Ransom was a senior at Vanderbilt University, 1908-1909.) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Prose: “Postscript” (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections, 16 pages. (See outgoing correspondence to Richard Wentworth of October 19, 1968 for Ransom’s comments on this essay.) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Prose: “Pound and Eliot” (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Typescript and holograph drafts and notes, 16 pages. Possibly part of “Fifty Years of American Verse.” (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Prose: “Religion and Poetry: Sisters But Not Twin Sisters” (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Typescript with corrections (lacks first page), and holograph notes, probably of a speech, c. 1958, 20 pages. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prose: “The Religion of the Poets” (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections, 9 pages. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Prose: “Theory of Poetic Form” (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections, 9 pages. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Prose: Untitled (T.S. Eliot) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Typescript and holograph drafts and notes of a paper or lecture about T.S. Elliot, 33 pages. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Prose: Untitled (Theodore Roethke) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Typescript with corrections of a paper about Theodore Roethke, 12 pages. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Prose: Untitled (Wallace Stevens and William Carlos Williams) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Typescript fragment with corrections (lacks first page) of a speech or lecture about Wallace Stevens and William Carlos Williams, c. 1963, 16 pages. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified typescript and holograph fragments and notes, 22 pages. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Published Works: Chills and Fever (1924) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Ransom’s annotated copy. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Published Works: Two Gentlemen In Bonds (1927) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ransom’s annotated copy. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Published Works: Poems And Essays (1955) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Ransom’s annotated copies, (2). (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Published Works: “Introduction” Selected Poems of Thomas Hardy “Introduction,” Selected Poems of Thomas Hardy (1961), pages iii-xxxiii initialed by Ransom. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Published Works: “The Planetary Poet” (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Pages 233-264 from the Kenyon Review (Winter, 1964). (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Published Works: “The State of Letters” (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Pages 548-550, source unknown, of Ransom’s acceptance speech for the National Book Award, 1964. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Published Works: Selected Poems (1969, 3rd Edition) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ransom’s annotated copy. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series III: Academics
  - Catalogs (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The School of Letters, Indiana University (1951, 1963, 1969) Piedmont School Manifesto (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Class rolls (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English 259 (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English K581, Indiana University (Summer, 1958) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - English 715, 2nd Quarter (1960-1961) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Kenyon College (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Honors Committee Report (1940) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Kenyon School of English Catalog (1949) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of the Faculty Committee (1956) Commencement Program (1959) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Notes (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Programs (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Sixteenth Peters Rushton Seminar in Contemporary Prose and Poetry (1958) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Southern Literary Festival, Mississippi State College for Women, Columbus, MS (1964) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Poetry Day, Lamar State College of Technology (1964) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The International Poetry Forum Presents John Crowe Ransom in the First Annual Institute on Poetics (1967) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The International Poetry Forum, Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh (1967) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Florida Writers’ Conference, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL (1970) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Prospectus for a Conference on Religion and Literature Conducted by the Church Society for College Work (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Publications Received (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Belhaven Briefs, (Belhaven College Newsletter, Jackson, MS, Spring, 1974) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bulletin of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Nov. 1972, Mar. 1973) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Christ Church, (1961, 1966) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous from the Institute of Contemporary Arts (2 items) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous announcements from Alfred A. Knopf (5 items) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Prospectus from New American Review (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Publisher’s announcements from New Directions (2 items) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - D.S. Berman Elizabeth Brown Thomas A. Claire (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Charles Frederick McKinley (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ralph Treitel (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography (c. 1964), 3 copies (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Syllabus (Eng. XV, Instructor Mr. Mott) Poems by Thomas Hardy (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Survey on Current English Usage by Raymond D. Crisp, 1971. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Author
  - Lists (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - List of Ransom essays (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - List of Ransom poems (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - List of various writers and works (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Financial and Contractual (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Royalty Statements (Knopf, 1949-1953), 4 items (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Contract (University of Minnesota, 1962) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Permission to Quote (Vanderbilt University, 1967) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Series VI: Editor
  - Kenyon Review (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Statement of Income and Disbursements, (July 1, 1957-June 30, 1958) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Series VI: Biographical
  - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Review of Poems About God, San Francisco Chronicle, 1919. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Ghosts,” printed in Harp er’s, 1926. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Review of God Without Thunder, New York Herald Tribune, 1931. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Memorial to Dr. John J. Ransom, Nashville Tennessean, 1934. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Discovery Wonderful Says Poet in UR Visit,” Richmond News, 1958. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - “Teacher, Ex-Pupil at Kenyon Talk Only Poetry,” Columbus Citizen Journal, 1968. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fragment of book review of Beating the Bushes and two other books about Ransom from Georgia Review, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Revision copy for a new cumulated edition of Contemporary Authors, c. 1965. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Family Papers (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ransom’s Marriage Certificate (1920) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Report Cards for Robb Reavill (1909-1913), 5 items (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Transcript (Columbia University, 1946) and Air Force Orders (1945) for Reavill (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Ransom (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Webb School Catalog (c. 1945) and Statement (1950), and Ohio State University (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - grades for John James (“Jack”) Ransom. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Financial Papers (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cancelled checks, deposit slips, bank statements, savings passbooks, nursing home bills (Annie Ransom), receipts, tax receipts, notes (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Memorabilia (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Typescripts of telegrams (35) received for the 1937 dinner honoring Ransom (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Program for the “Dinner in Honor of the Fugitives, Belle Meade Club” (1956) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Notes (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 13 holograph items (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Passenger List, White Star Line, M.V. Britannic from New York to Liverpool (1931) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Pedigree for Mosnar Jane, The Kennel Club, London (1932) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - West Cornwall Golf Club, Official Handbook (n.d.) Official Rules of Croquet (1951) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Application for Duplicate Driver’s License (Ransom, 1959) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Reservation Card (Harvard, 1966) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Child’s Drawing (Roland Camire?, n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Advertisement (Murray Corporation, n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Advertisement (Montaldo’s, n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Photographs (1 of 7) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 56 items, primarily of Ransom and various family members, especially his wife Robb and her relations. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Photographs (2 of 7) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Same as above. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Photographs (3 of 7) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Same as above. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Photographs (4 of 7) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Same as above. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (5 of 7) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Same as above. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (6 of 7) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Same as above. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (7 of 7) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Same as above. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series VII: Writings by Others
  - Manuscripts: Alrich, Virgil C. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - “Cultural Viscosity – A Brief Meditation” (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts: Barlow, Nathan L. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - “To Youth” “Love’s Creation” (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - “Remember, Solomon?” (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts: Benson, Anne (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “Summer Back Yard” “The Suitor” (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts: Berkwicz, Tom (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “Phoenix” “My Tongue” (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “Flat lies my breast...” (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “In golden oranges...” (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts: Buford, William (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - “The Ambassadors” (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts: Burke, Kenneth (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “Introduction to What” (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts: Das, Manas Mukul (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “Silence: The Language of Poetry” (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts: Davidson, Donald (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - “Introduction,” to a 1966 reprint of The Fugitive. Includes corrections. Photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts: Detlef, R.E. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - “Rumble” (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts: Drath, Wilfred (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - “Oedipus” (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - “Five Short Poems” (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts: Duncan, Robert (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - “The Truth and Life of Myth in Poetry”, Includes corrections, photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts: Feldman, Irving (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Poem” “The Heir” “Dunkerque 1951” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “The Word” “A Psalm” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Sea, Island, Night” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Dressing Hornpout” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “At Pasha’s Greek Gardens Cafe, 1954” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Party on East Tenth Street, 1955” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Reredos Showing the Assumption Into Heaven of Frank O’Hara” “Poet at Twelve” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “Dark Nights” (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts: Forman, Robb Reavill (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - “Summer’s End”, a 21 page recollection of family and summers at Gambier, OH by Ransom’s granddaughter. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts: Frost, Graham Nicol (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - “Golgotha” (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Manuscripts: Gjelsness, Barent (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “Quartet – 1963” (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “The Women of La Rochelle” “Wheatfields” (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “Pictures” “Analogy” (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “Snow Song” “Story” (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - “For Everyone” (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Manuscripts: Hemphill, George (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - “The First Draft of Lycidas” (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Manuscripts: Holladay, Helen H. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - “Vanity” (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Manuscripts: Hull, A.H. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - “Sun” “Wind” “Snow” (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - “Dew” “Clouds” (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - “Rain” “Fog” (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts: Hulbert, Russell (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - “Dialogue Upon A Fall” (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - “The Spring Has Come” “Song of Confederacy” (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - “The Professor and the Poet” (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - “Shakespeare” (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Manuscripts: Jacoby, Grover (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - “Translation from ‘The Antiquities of Rome’ (Du Bellay)” (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Manuscripts: Jewell, Therese (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - “Thomas Hardy’s Theological Dilemma As It Appears in The Dynasts and Selected Short Poems” (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Manuscripts: Levertov, Denise (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - “A Personal Approach”, fragment, photocopy. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Manuscripts: Lewis, Zella (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - “Summitry” “Sterling Circuit” “Circuit” (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Manuscripts: Lillit, Hazel Ransom (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - “Birthday Greeting” (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - “A Candle’s Message” (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Manuscripts: Logan, John (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - “Poem, Slow To Come, On The Death of Cummings (1896-1962)” (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Manuscripts: Lyle, David (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - “After Reading a Few of James Dickey’s Poems” “We Stop” (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - “I Am The Music” (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - “Listening” “Phantasma” “Poem” (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - “I Used to Make” “Autumn Day” (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Manuscripts: Montgomery, Marion (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - “A Summer of Words in A Formal Garden” “Prelude” (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - “As I Walk Toward The Formal Garden” “The New Riding Class” (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - “A Word in the Stone” “Miracle” (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - “Amber and Earth” (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - “Postlude” “Ed Krickel” (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Manuscripts: Mott, Michael (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - “The Climb” “Poets” (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - “Dream about my Brother” (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - “Glastonburry Tor” (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Manuscripts: O’Brien, Mike (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - “The little girl with chinese eyes” (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Manuscripts: O’Donnell, George Marion (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Return and Other Poems” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Return” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “John Sterling” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Autumn and Mrs. Noel, Old” “In the Delta, Remembering” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Letter for the Confederates” “Travelogue” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “August Afternoon” “Mask of Christ” “Injured Mind” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Season of Dying” “Lacking Art” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Letter From The Hills” “Ancestor” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Mirrored Dead” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “The Rivals of My Watch” “Jefferson Davis in Stone” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “The Negress and the Astronomer” “Two Poems for a Season of Holiday” “Descent of Leaf” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Reprimand” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - “Elegy” (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Manuscripts: Olsen, Karen (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Manuscripts: Pearce, Roy (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - “Lord Randall, My Friend...” (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Manuscripts: Petitjean, A.M. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Translation of “Captain Carpenter” into French (See correspondence from Henry Church for further information.) (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Manuscripts: Richards, I.A. (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - “Content” (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - “End of a Course” (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Manuscripts: Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - “Essay” (On “Master’s in the Garden Again”) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Manuscripts: Simmons, J. Edgar (1 of 9) (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - “Abstraction” (Box 6, Folder 40)